so let's now Define what does it mean
for caches to be coherent intuitively
they're coherent when the whole thing
behaves like there was no caches but
let's define more precisely what exactly
does it mean there are three
requirements for coherence the first one
says that the read let's call that read
R from some address X on some core C1
will return the value written by the
most recent WR let's call that right W
to the same location and that right was
on the same core C1 if no other core has
written to that location between the
axises W and R so this first part of the
coherence definition really says that if
one core is operating on a location
alone then its reads should be getting
the most recent rides from the same core
this basically says that a coherent
Behavior includes correct unit processor
Behavior as long as the location is
accessed by only one core the second
part of the definition says that if core
C1 wres to allocation X and C2 reads X
after a sufficient time and if there are
no other rights that happen in between
c1s right and c2's read then c2's read
must return the value C1 wrote so pretty
much if there is a right and the read
happens sufficiently after that right
then the read has to read what the right
wrote except if there was another right
in between in which case the read is
allowed to return that value instead of
this one so this part of the definition
really prevents the case when for
example C1 writes something to its own
cache C2 reads forever from its cache a
stale value to be
coherent if C1 wres then after some
sufficient time C2 must start reading
the new value even if maybe a normal
cache with no coherence support would
just keep reading the stale value
because it never gets replaced so we
have to do something in order to make
this part of the definition work for
private caches that are caching data in
a coherent system so we must do
something to make these caches behave
this way and finally the third part of
the the definition says that if there is
more than one right to the same location
then these rights must be serialized
that is any two rights to the same
location must be seen to occur in the
same order on all the cores what this
part of the definition really says
different cores should not be able to
disagree about which right occurred
first and which occurred second note
that the second part of the definition
doesn't really require this to happen
let's say there was one right on C1 and
another right on C3 when C2 reads it's
allowed to return after a sufficient
time either c1s or c3's value because
it's allowed to interpret this order as
either C1 and then C3 wrote or the other
way around what this part of the
definition says is that whatever C2 sees
if C2 for example CES that the final
value is that from C1 and not from C3
then all the other cores when they read
that location after C2 need to also see
that order so it cannot happen that C2
thinks C1 wrote last some other core
sometime later reads and still sees c3's
value so what this is really saying is
that everybody including the writing
course will see the value that is
consistent with their being some
particular order to the rights it
doesn't require any particular order for
example the rights can happen almost
simultaneously in which case we are free
to choose which happen first and which
happen second but we cannot allow some
cores to think that one right was first
and other cores think that another right
was first